MAGDA GONZALEZ

Monterrey, 64619

Phone: 8116361799| Email: magda.p.gonzalez.s@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://bit.ly/34zO9P0 | GitHub: https://bit.ly/3gfqbiu

SUMMARY

Industrial Designer with 8+ years of experience in analytics & digital solutions. Skills in Excel, VBA, Python, SQL, JavaScript, from Tecnológico de Monterrey: 'Data Analytics & Visualization Bootcamp'. Ability to gather data & transform it into innovative digital opportunities. With a small budget developed the new mobile site and digital sales strategies through Facebook Ads that increased sales in the company's different branches. Recently completed a Digital Marketing certification in Emeritus Institute of Management from Columbia University. It's important to highlight that in the Stukent simulations got the 1st place in Google Ads and in Social Media content the 7th of 85 students who completed the certification. Fast learner with the ability to solve complex projects with a holistic view, taking into account final user, teammates & company, through a user experience approach and abilities combined with collaborating across diverse groups, makes me a valuable addition to any team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Tools: Excel VBA, Python, Pandas, Matplotlib, JSON, SQL, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, MongoDB, ETL, JavaScript, Tableau, Leaflet, R, Google Adwords, Google Analytics, Google Data Studio, Facebook Ads, Excel, Wordpress, Instapage, Adobe

PROJECT

Netflix Productions | GitHub: https://bit.ly/3gfqbiu | Project: https://bit.ly/2YIZ0L0

- Obtain the numbers behind one of the most popular streaming services and prove that even though Netflix promotes content and culture diversity, it's still mainly US productions and western culture.
- Extract the data, transform the data bye cleaning it, and load it into the final database.
- Python and SQL

EXPERIENCE

Marketing Manager Grupo Autofin Monterrey

2017 – Present Monterrey, Nuevo León

Part of a small team who's responsible of analyzing recent trends to develop, maintain and evaluate digital sales strategies that improve the 6 group units and used to work with tight deadlines. Experienced in implementing and leading digital sales projects. Convinced the company to redesign and improve the entire digital customer experience. In collaboration with an external partner we used the scrum framework to cross-functionally collaborate with the different business branches to reengineer all the digital channels (web page, mobile app, & social media) based on the AIDA Sales Funnel, Fogg Behavior Model and MVP. Improve the quality of the interaction and perception in the digital channels through UI/UX experience & 5 Second Usability Tests.

Key Contributions

- •Analyzed insights from previous external and internal platforms to deliver a desktop and mobile webpage that has efficiently increased the number of leads(from 5,600 to 16,800 per month). (https://autofinauto.com/)
- •Defined a digital sales strategy that with a small monthly budget of \$60 USD (395 DKK) per store (58 stores) brought a return only in Facebook Ads of \$6,600,000 USD (43,521,390 DKK) in 2018. And in 2019 with the same budget the return has been of \$10,400,000 USD (68,579,160 DKK). Cancelation rate was decreased to 90%.
- •Improved user experience in the entire digital channels which helped the company to provide a better client service.
- •Created and executed in the real estate unit a digital strategy that sold 45 apartments out of 56 in 5 months. The strategy included: Facebook, Instagram, Google, design and development of landing page. (http://praxys.mx/)
- •Developed strong team that has implemented reputation, branding and customer oriented efforts.

MAGDA GONZALEZ

Monterrey, 64619

Phone: 8116361799| Email: magda.p.gonzalez.s@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://bit.ly/34zO9P0 | GitHub: https://bit.ly/3gfqbiu

Marketing Manager Midas International NOV 2016 – MAY 2017 Monterrey, Nuevo León

Recruited to establish an efficient team to execute branding, PR, events, marketing collateral development, and online transformation. Managed budget from \$55,000 USD (363,167 DKK). Redesigned UI/UX and implemented the company's desktop and mobile website.

Key Contributions

- •Responsible of a rebranding strategy that elevated the company's profile, which was not aligned with the Midas International corporate image. This helped to improve the public perception and increased service appointments & franchise sales.
- •Delivered a desktop and mobile webpage that efficiently increased the number of appointments (280 to 728 per month by state). (https://www.midas.com.mx/)
- •Assisted the franchise members and assessed their marketing needs which build a strong relationship between them and corporate office.
- •Grew the firm's efficiency by recruiting top candidates.

Research Analyst Chubb

OCT 2014 – NOV 2016 Monterrey, Nuevo León

Hired as a part of the marketing intelligence team to develop in-depth competition analysis, spot recent trends, generate reports, and improve internal communications of the American Express projects. Conducted research that obtained partners, customers and strengthened the company at a global level.

Key Contributions

- •Used user experience and design thinking to create and execute a platform that managed organization's innovation team proposals, which delivered \$15,000 USD (98,917 DKK) savings.
- •Used Data Visualization and Storytelling to deliver business insights which improved communication across Chubb, Citibanamex and AMEX that helped them made faster and better decisions.
- •In-depth analysis of user needs and competition that aided all the areas of the company that helped their product development strategies.

User Experience Designer Egade Business School

FEB 2013 - OCT 2014 Monterrey, Nuevo León

Joined to research business school event's offering and competition to develop effective rebranding strategies which led to a successful, innovative, and dynamic format of the event that attracted more than 1,400 business leaders and delivered savings of \$125,000 USD (825,473 DKK) for the school.

Key Contributions

- •Analysis of service to redefine accuracy, which led to an assistance of more than 1,400 business leaders of the Top 100 Mexican companies.
- •Rebranded event's image and designed ATL, BTL & TTL materials.
- •Developed UI/UX for the website.
- Coordinated suppliers & assisted speakers/sponsors.

Research and Product Designer Whirlpool Corporation

JAN 2012-DEC 2012

Benton Harbor, Michigan

Use of "Design Thinking" and "Persona" methodologies to deliver innovative beverage dispensers, with a universal visual language that improved user experience through usability. Product design from early concept to final delivery which included research, 3D visualization of proposals, rough prototyping, selection of sustainable materials, and branding initiative aligned to company's strategic business plan.

Key Contributions

- •Master's project completed in less than 12 months when it was meant to be a 2 years project.
- •Shared globally through the company's different branches for its research and design value.
- •One of the concepts was developed and launched in 2016.

MAGDA GONZALEZ

Monterrey, 64619

Phone: 8116361799| Email: magda.p.gonzalez.s@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://bit.ly/34zO9P0 | GitHub: https://bit.ly/3gfqbiu

EDUCATION

24-week intensive Analytics & Visualization Bootcamp, (JAN 2020-Present) TECNOLÓGICO DE MONTERREY

Digital Marketing: Customer Engagement, Social Media, Planning & Analytics (2019) EMERITUS INSTITUTE OF MANAGEMENT, COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY

Service Innovation (2014), Social Responsibility (2014), Consumer Behavior (2014) EGADE BUSINESS SCHOOL

> Master in Industrial Design and Product Innovation (2012) TECNOLÓGICO DE MONTERREY

> Bachelor of Industrial Design (Honorable Mention) (2011)
> TECNOLÓGICO DE MONTERREY

LANGUAGES

English: Full Professional Proficiency, 6 of 7 in IBO test German: Level A1

Danish: Level A1